A referee is Ben O'Keefe from New Zealand.
Touched judges, Matiore Nel, James Dolman.
Brandon Pickle is a TV match official.
BELL RINGS
Number one in the world, Ireland.
Take on the defending champion, South Africa.
It's a pull-beam match, which could easily be as tight as a facelift.
Welcome to start to France, straight away.
It's Simon Villosa into the Freyhees up, ended.
South Africa in their white jersey.
Their third strip at this Rugby World Cup.
Buf the clerk, looking to go wide early on.
And it's been spilled on that part of the side by Cheson Colby.
Ambitious, soon to South Africa, straight off the start.
The kick from Milan comes straight down the middle.
I think Buf the clerk, just a little bit of extra nervous energy
in that pass, probably overcooked a little bit.
Normally so efficient at getting out of this part of the field to South Africa.
Oh, look, he's glad to take him off. Here's go.
He's taken it.
Time off.
Look at this for a statement off the opening chase.
Thumbs off.
It's Callaghan, gets the water technique in the tackle.
Drives Villosa back.
I think we've got a little bit of an early issue for Josh Vandervele here.
He's getting a bit of treatment.
Chalking over.
Head coach took the role in 2020.
He needs his position after this World Cup to replace to a Lancaster
head coach, Andy Farrell, there since 2016 as an assistant,
but head coach since 2019.
And he's 33 out of 40 tests.
I mean, that is an outstanding record.
He's going very smartly indeed.
But this is the biggest test of all, the Rugby World Cup.
This crowd is absolutely electric.
I tell you what,
Ireland's warm-up song today was Smoke on the Water by Deep Purple.
But in this stadium at the moment, it is a sea of green.
They were expecting around 30,000 Irish fans to come to start to France today.
But it certainly sounds like war.
It is absolutely incredible.
The pitch side.
You need his undone.
Pinch at the line of time for South Africa.
He comes away though.
For Ireland, down the right there.
Gives him park, shifts it.
Fords looking for some work around the fringes.
Tight burn.
Such an experienced player.
Puts his head down, does the monster man.
Gives him park yet again to the left.
That's at the Gary Ringrose.
Cuts it nicely into the 22.
It's Ireland now.
They're building their phases nicely early on.
Burn again for the second carry.
Sexton finds his full back.
You go Keenan.
Burn is one, rolling into the nine.
Such a cunning player with advantage to the Irish side now.
Furlong turns it to Bundy Aki.
He's 50th international for his country.
Ireland go to the right.
It's a big pass.
A lot of time.
The one who just won the wrong side and rolled into number nine.
Will stay with Ireland.
An early look at that Ireland attack.
The deception at play is quite fantastic.
Already we've seen those passes.
Fizzed across the front of players.
As a defender, it looks like they're going to receive it.
And then it goes to the next man.
Keeping on their rock speed as well.
Ireland's rock speed so far.
Fastest in the tournament.
Less than three seconds per run.
And they are here to play.
Sexton will pop this one in the corner.
OK, Jimmy, good space.
Good sit-up.
We've got the two by two for the nine.
One of the 7000 Irish bars around the globe.
Certainly enjoying this endeavour from the Irish side.
How many?
Four matches.
Four in the middle.
More passes in those two games than they did
in the whole of the last rugby walk-up.
To the front they go.
Tideburn, Clon Pinch.
And it's Hoof downfield by Colby.
Not out.
Left behind from Mack Hansen.
All's gone backwards in the touch.
Happy there, Jimmy.
Spots a bit of space.
And it's an awkward bounce,
but it's good for South Africa.
Krill's on the inside.
Big Jesse Krill into the 22.
And a clean-up from Dio Lendi.
Through the legs it goes.
Seven-style play there from Fuff De Clac.
Game back on, Jasper Visser.
South Africa now.
Their chance to attack.
Big step, Damien Vonser.
Does one side of the 22.
The ball is now for the spring box.
He re-advanced.
De Clac works the short side to his captain,
Siaf Conlici.
Got the penalty.
Bungie and the Nambi.
Big carry from the Hooker.
Visser again for the second time.
Ireland's wall holding strong.
Here comes Yvan Etzebeth.
Man, that's built like a Bulgarian
vending machine.
To the right it goes again.
Krill trying to skip through.
Not back.
And it will be a penalty
for South Africa.
It's a turning opening.
Four minutes.
Green straight at the top of feet.
To me.
Shot there.
He's getting some treatment on the ground now.
Got hit a little bit late.
I think James Ryan went straight through him.
There.
The eyes up to the coaching box
to see what kind of
shots called.
Two metres.
There's the ambition
from South Africa.
It's a pretty loose kick,
but the bounce did
answer a favour.
We're rolling this.
He dished it back inside to Krill
who was supporting
Ringrose with the scramble tackle
and nearly on the pinch.
We didn't see anything.
It was furious, wasn't it?
From South Africa.
A little look at
a bit of afters.
South Africa, area which they've struggled in
this Rugby World Cup.
10 out of 18 kicks.
They've used Manila Bakkenpik's
shot.
It's a big part
of winning Rugby World Cup matches.
It's at the
far from the Stormers.
South Africa's
first shot a goal.
Manila Bak turns.
The flags go up.
South Africa have the opening points
in this game.
They lead on at 3-0 off to 5.
There's the
infringement.
A nice one for Manila Bakkenpik.
He's been backed by coach and captain
in terms of his kicking.
He's only on a 40% kicking
stat.
Manila Bakkenpik's
shot.
Sexta.
Down the middle.
South Africa needs 3-0.
Franco Mostert is there.
He plays his rugby with the heat in Japan.
Can he use it?
50th cap
against Scotland during this Rugby World Cup.
Six seasons with the spring box.
He goes to the air.
Colby comes down.
A bunch of green jerseys.
They have it at the halfway line.
Jamison Gibson Park.
There's Scrum off.
One of
an instrument
in the starting
side.
Very familiar with their team.
Sexton tries to get it away.
Flying in.
Penal the island.
No
attempt to catch the ball.
We just hit that on the short pass.
And
it's over.
He only
plays outside.
It's
really fascinating
little tactical battle.
Ireland
playing with that flat attack.
Sexton taking it right
close to the line.
Against the line speed of South Africa.
It's a real challenge.
He holds his feet still to try and play around
the line.
It's a
challenge.
It flies off the line.
Such an acceleration.
As the Scrum off.
They've had trouble.
Two knock-ons.
Sexton
Stavriga Scrum.
Heol.
Scrums to
the deck.
Leah Jubrek Dum Durr.
We'll be
making the calls.
Scrum the Yorkside.
Their
such a great speed,
match-ups we set. Scrum time. 34 scrumps this year coming into this tournament out of 34 but
they lost one of their own against Romania and one against Scotland.
Arlen, you pulled it back and went early. Next one's up in early. Wait for Michael.
We'll get to the spring box.
Now the scrum. Yep, we all came in early okay. Wait for the call. I'm waiting for stability.
Then I'll call set. I'll be louder. I will.
Next one's a penalty. Wait for the timing of the call.
Kitter wants to go again. I'd say furl, I wouldn't mind a bit of that.
They all looked around in this one. Take two.
Two.
Keep it up now.
Chesham Colby lurking behind from the clock. It's scrum time. Vissa picks up.
Bashes his way upfield.
Looks for Peter Steff to toy. Is that out because rugby player the year three times.
Okay, use it.
Pops one high again.
Another excellent taker, then absolutely eaten on the ground. Here's Mack Hansen. Arlen.
You're fine. You're on the wrong side. You've got to roll quicker if I want to reward two.
You're okay. It's just fours on the wrong side.
Nice explained by Ben O'Keefe. The Jackal. Bungie on Benambi on the Jackal, which was legit.
I was really happy with that contest. I thought he was off your arm. I thought your elbow was up as
well. Thank you. But it was even. It's the best. Just lying on the wrong side.
Tim to be creating a hurdle. We're playing guys. What about that scrum?
The Irish forwards reckon that they took great confidence from that win against South Africa
back in November. Even a couple of the backs have attended the scrum sessions this week.
So some education in the dark arts. Of course, South Africa posed such a physical challenge,
but they're also technically smart. So this is going to be a huge challenge for Ireland.
Yeah, not there. They look on some of the extras. 11 plays from Ireland. 11 from South
Africa. He played in that last game. Well, here tonight. 1960 was a score there. Arlen winning
by three. Traditionally been very close encounters over the top, though. The fourth line-up goes
right for Andy Farrell's side. A worrying point for them so far in this game.
To Clack for the touch line this time. Nice clearance from the scrum off.
Yes, lovely. Tekkers from Fafda Klark there. He managed to get his side up towards the 10th
from that position. He's admirable. Real concern for this Ireland line-up, though.
And perhaps South Africa won't mind pumping the ball at the sideline.
Continue to put threat. They're going to go for a five-man line-out.
See if they can get it right this time. Pressure on Kelleher.
25 year old. He's 24th cap for Ireland. Can he find? He's Mark.
Yes, is the answer. Guido Manny with a great take in his 100th appearance.
And now, flat ball in the middle from Sexton. Changes direction. Ring Rose throws a dummy.
Ireland carry-worth. James Ryan plays play of the Ufra Ireland in 2019.
Khaleesi, a real nuisance around the breakdown.
Sexton. Nice dummy. Couple of fakes and they go over the top. Here comes Ireland now.
Beautiful but a word. Keenan. The fox gets very close. Does Hugo Keenan?
Akir is in there as well. Kelleher on the right. Here come the Irish now. Kaelan Doris.
They get very, very close.
And that's off the back of a fabulous sequence of attack. They managed to get the line-out
right this time. And then they were off and running. What about the throw over the top?
The punt. And then that perfectly played ball. It's Keenan with the fend, the pirouette, and oh,
so close. Guys, time's not up. Let's go, please. Speaking to Andy Farrell pre-match, even he wasn't
sure if they were going to be able to play that attacking attractive rugby that they have played
in the first two games, given the physicality of the South African side,
but it's pretty clear the intent is there already, as we say Andre Pollard there.
He's going to come back into the South African squad officially as a replacement for Malcolm Marx.
Good hide this side.
Great audio there from the crowd. And as you said, Andre Pollard.
Amazing addition for Sherab Gussite. Kick 22 points to the regular World Cup final in 2019
against England. Recovered from his car. Kennedy South Africa. It's gone tight.
You've gone again twice. It's now a penalty, yes. Wait for my call, please.
Another early engagement identification from referee Ben O'Keefe. I don't think there's a
problem when they're down scrumming in at the moment. It's just the process. Obviously not
quite O'Feefe with Mr O'Keefe's calls or something, but I need you to be able to adapt to the call.
It's slow. I'm waiting for balance, and then you can go, okay? I saw Green come first, okay?
Please adapt, thank you. Often it's because they're so desperate to meet the hit against a strong
scrumming side. They don't want to lose that initial hit, but at the moment they're going early.
So they're able to get their line with Itzebeth in the front.
Khaleesi now in midfield with courageous captain. Tackle! Got his knee on the ground. Tackle!
Being pinched. Off the middle come Ireland. Tight burn. And then Ireland lose it.
He did well to stop. He was on the ground, so Tackle, did you get a turn over? You had a good turn
over. Knock on. Can I get my wrist? Give it to you, go.
There's a crisp seed from Levotte to his skipper. Talked to Rowan in timing. And he was met pretty
smartly by Callan Doris. They try and do the hold up. Eventually it ends up being a ruck.
Time off. And then Burn gets the steal, and it's the off load from Doris. I think he might have
dropped one close to the line. He's shelled another. It was good defensive work. They'll be
encouraged by that. Turn over first phase. The bomb squad, seven and one split on the bench.
So much chat about that, of course, since they used it against New Zealand in the warm-ups.
Ireland. Seating at a premium on that bench with seven forwards, taking up all the space.
Tobias Ryan have the only lucky back to make the cut. But I love it,
Darlin, because I think it reminds us that Rugby is about the skill set, not just the number on
your back. I think that's a useful thing to remind youngsters of. I don't think too much about the
position you're playing. It's as much just what you bring to the game. You bring that wherever
you play. Yeah, you're right. Some opposition fans question the decision. But as nervous as the
long-tailed cat in the room, filled with rocking chairs, but it worked for them in the past.
Innovation is good for the game. Breaking the mould as we've seen this in the Afrika
Tendu before. It's creative. Okay, let's get set and then I'll call it back on.
We'll see how it goes over the course of this game.
Jacques Nainibur admit that there was an element of risk to picking a seven-one split on the bench,
but there's an element of risk in everything in Rugby. You could get a red card early,
so it was a risk they were willing to take. Yeah, you're so right now. That's true.
Nina Arbor and the Russians, the Brainstrust of the spring box.
Played in seven of the nine Rugby World Cups. Up the clock, comes to Vilmsa.
Played fly off as well early in this tournament. Damian Vilmsa does really well. Both full backs,
having some strong feet. Here comes the giant frame of Itzebeth that takes his shot as well to the
ground. The clock. Wanting quicker ball for Livok to attack with. Here comes Umbanami.
Wide ball from Fuff. Binds, Ardensup. Good tackle. Loewe gets in as well. It's Ireland.
Let's stop this attack and draw a penalty as well.
What do you think? Back three players get particularly fired up when they get turned over.
The James does really good over the ball. He's also got an absolutely monster boot on him.
He's pretty smart with ball in hand as well. Such a weapon for this Irish side.
The defence has been good. The opening, 16 or so minutes of this game.
He's got his work hard on the step here. Mets you, everyone at the front.
It's the second time tonight.
It's in Vilmsa. Get his naughty feet out. There's the turnover. Manages to get
hand on the ball. Look at that. Supporting his own weight. Nice and low. Great technique.
So here we go. Ken, Ronan, Kelaert.
Andrew, come down. Continue to get line of possession here.
It's the Irish side that won 27 of 29 games in the last two years, only losing to
New Zealand and France. Seat up off the mark. Managed to work a five-man line earlier with
a bit of movement and that was the key. It's good now.
Again, it's movement. This time they come right to the front. Secure ball.
Kelaert rips it away. Aki, steaming in. What a bulldozer he is for the Irish side,
but it's South Africa that are all over this one as well.
Both sides, when he break down penalties. Sevens on the good side. Nine. Careful,
you've got the penalty. Here it is. Tide, drop the ball.
The wrath on the wrist, but Faftaclack for rubbing it in.
We've got the ball as well. We're having a penalty here.
Expect nothing less.
Sort of a bandy Aki coming on that hard line. I mean, he has been ridiculous so far.
They've had two fairly comfortable games, but in those games he's gone for about 268 meters,
which is top of the tree. I think he's been praised by anyone who's had him in their fantasy team,
because he's been scoring points wholesale in that.
Yeah, he's a player. You do not look past.
Six and also collecting a ton of points for the Irish side last time.
The book finds Aronsa, a flat ball. Jesse Krill comes flying in.
The Clack again. Nice ball on the inside. Peter Steff to tweak.
And it's the spring box now. We find themselves on the front foot.
Nibbana, the exibit in there as well.
Between the legs.
Behind the back to Djalendi, puts one to the ground.
And the inside centre. He's a bulky frame as well.
The hands down the chain.
A kick through from Damien Villemser.
And he has timed that to perfection.
A real celebration. The perfect kick. Just staying the right side of that flag in the corner.
Trouble for Gary Ringrose.
Ireland's line at five out. Stay in the 15. Again, short in numbers to try to secure position.
James Ryan is accurate. Gibson Park moves it away. Here comes Kaelin Doris.
25 year old. Ireland's set up. Again, user nine.
No, it's not, it's not.
Great Bear Ireland in New Zealand.
As that one charged down.
He was onside the whole time. Thank you, Johnny.
That's a big obstacle, isn't it, when you're trying to box out of there.
Putman, I keep it to you, he's offside, but just about right side of the line.
It's a real loose as a line-up time as well, even at Tibet.
In accuracy, at line-up time for Ireland. Could be very costly in this game.
This the last attack for South Africa. The angle. Grills coming on there.
It's really nice on the sleight of hands from Marnie LeBotte.
That's the one that left Gary Ringrose feeling a little bit rusty.
Tried to put the big shot on Damien D'Elendi.
Not easy to do the... Okay, 13 green. Sub, HIA.
In fact, Ringrose is going off for an HIA.
All good, you're onside, Jimmy.
Tried to hit D'Elendi. 106 kg or so.
In the mould of Jean de Villiers, you might say, who sat behind us here in the Coventry Box.
Not a bad replacement for Robbie Hinge, there as well, for Gary Ringrose.
Same message timing.
Brian, a disc of the great Irish legend that's here as well. Didn't bring his boots, he said.
Still a rugby World Cup record holder with the Irish side.
We've never got past a quarter-farmers, in fact.
He wouldn't believe that, seeing the form of this Irish side.
Robbie Hinge, you're coming in, and he'll need all 70 caps experience,
now 71 to defend this scrum.
The clap feeds for South Africa. They're up 3-0.
21 minutes gone. D'Elendi goes up for Olders.
D'Elendi within 3 metres. South Africa on the verge of scoring.
Peter steps the toy still, and the ball's been pinched as well.
That is excellent from Ireland.
You're on the tackle, you gripped it back.
South Africa scrum taken back.
South Africa scrum.
No, it's been ripped by Greenie Levin, and it's gone back into in goal.
Oh, come on, D'Elendi is taking out Ireland players, one by one.
Jimmy.
Hanhila got pre-calling now, I'm pretty sure he was saying,
you come back against the angle, and he almost pre-called the step.
Running into Johnny Sexton, he put a good shot of contact,
but it's come off second best.
James Low in there again, doing a bit of a back row work.
That's why we've got time off.
Maybe it's safe.
I don't want your players to be scammed and causing stuff afterwards.
OK, you know what will happen.
Thank you.
Real warring times for Johnny Sexton, the captain of Ireland.
One of the most decorated players in the world.
He's for Frankie Wilcoff.
OK, sit down, time's going back home, please.
Ireland, time's going back home, please.
Well, when the ball's live, this game is being played at a brilliant pace.
OK.
A great tempo.
Agree, but when I have the ball in the back row, I'll say, use it,
and I'll put you for the conscious.
French legend, he's all the way...
No, no, he's taken back into the goal by Green.
I heard you, I heard you, Bongie, I heard you, OK.
Let's go, there's the Marcus in the middle.
Other legers in the house, goal-foot, Rory McElroy.
Other legers in the house, goal-foot, Rory McElroy from Ireland.
Michael Flamley, the silver-red Irish dancers here as well.
Just a bit, just a bit.
See the way Manila Bocke's just got his eyes widened at this area of the park
when he knows he's getting the chance to create something
just at his fast-paced, energising presence in this African backline.
And he's got Williamson behind him here.
Goals!
Fyne!
Six!
The Sprengloch options, both sides.
Fyne, two feet.
The clock. Short ball.
Jesse Kirl, very close.
Khaleesi loses it.
Ireland have it.
Verkhart, celebrating.
No advantage over.
The way they repel the Sprengbox, but it's not out.
Verkhart, big step of his left.
Get should have won.
Does the fullback for South Africa.
Visa.
Skip's master goes to Steven Kitzoff, the one they call the angry plump.
Khaleesi takes, goes low.
Bounces out of a couple, and a spill has come in there as well.
Please don't run into him.
I did not see him move.
This is the set-piece.
There's Creel again.
Piercing through the middle.
What a tackle from Bundy Arke.
Chops him down.
Eyes on, gets low, takes the legs.
That is fabulous.
From both centres.
For all money, that was going to be a score.
And here's the turnover.
Just a little knock-on in there.
James Lowe's fired up, and why not?
The Island defence keeping them out just about at the moment.
Their timing's much better on them, good patience.
That's the call.
Coach!
Fine!
Sixth!
Left side.
Full noise.
Here it starts to france.
Sexton works it wide.
Okay, nine-hold.
Kick down field by Hugo Keenan, the former Sevens International.
And Island work their way up the field.
Okay, Jimmy, control that mark.
We need to have good care for this line-up.
That's lefty.
Yep.
Yeah, there's now.
Okay, we must have good space.
The South African backdoor obviously starting back to cover the kick,
but as the Island attack is, and the back shift it...
Island!
...means the back three of South Africa have to come up,
which then leaves that backfield space.
As you think, Hugo Keenan, he's so skilful,
he probably would have wanted that to roll into the 22
by his own standards.
He's been so impressive, really making that 15 jersey his own.
So there we go.
Solid with Khaleesi.
Sataku, no, your hands are...
No, yeah, thank you.
Clack.
Manila Boc goes to the sky.
Kurtly Aronsa comes down.
Oh, what a contest that is.
Aronsa wins it.
Another international Sevens player,
lining it up here at the Rugby World Cup.
Low thought about a kick,
and then the Dunny, and he's been had by Vilymsa.
Island under pressure in their 22.
Josh Van der Flair with a red gear is there as well.
World Rugby player of the year in 2022.
Sexta just telling his forwards and backs where to go.
No, take your step, five, five, four.
Jamison gets some part.
Use it, nine.
No, you're still off.
Take your step behind the foot.
It's a bit gets close, puts under.
Pressure.
On the ground, knocked on by a South Africa.
Goes forward in the air.
That's a cool thing.
Almost peeled out.
Never think that must be.
For Gibson Park, trying to box.
Kick under that pressure, and that's a bit...
You go keen, and potentially...
Playing Ironser in the air there.
Got that pressure.
I mean, that causes Gibson Park to have to put thumbs off.
Different trajectory on his kicks.
He's got to almost go straight up in the air,
which is why the ball dropped only about 10 metres ahead
of where the rock was.
But Irish Chase is able to get up and make a mess of it.
Yes, so electric to see Kurt Lee, Ironser, 12 tries in 12 games.
You mentioned you go keen, and he's been 10 tries
on his score for his country.
You see a lot of the games coming here next year to France,
to this very stadium.
Sevens will be played here.
Inside, start to France.
What an occasion.
We're going to restart the scrum.
On the ball.
They'll be here watching the sevens in the Olympics next year.
No doubt.
He's going to be kicking off the Olympics.
Feet under you, yes, the message.
Feet under.
Next year.
His feet need to come under.
Your elbow needs to come up, that's the message, OK?
A tidbit for you guys.
Willie LaRue is not in the 22 today.
23 today, I should say,
but he was running the water for South Africa.
A couple of experienced watercourses.
He's got to be able to get up and make a mess of it.
A couple of experienced watercourses out there,
because it's Keith Earl's, I think,
down there as well, running water for Ireland.
So, a couple of useful, wise old heads.
Guys, we're running the water on both teams.
Let's go. This is it, please.
We've been waiting too long.
Who said the scrum? We've got the ball.
Nearly half an hour play at 3-0.
South Africa lead, Ireland.
Typically low affairs.
Only once in 117 years of history of this fixture.
There's a team produced more than 50 points.
It's back in 2016.
32-26, South Africa won that one there last time.
They've beaten the Irish, Gibson Park, rolls it backwards.
Aki again, burst to the line.
Bundy Aki looking to go over the half-way line.
Aki is a sensation in this game.
Into the 22 for Ireland.
Gibson Park saw a bunch of water.
He's flying up on the right-hand side.
Numbers to the left.
Porter for Ireland.
Can they capitalise on their break by Bundy Aki?
He carries again.
Delayed ball.
You know, Manny's there.
Much better from this Irish side.
A second carry again from Andrew Porter.
David in 2017.
Sexton crunched as he gives the inside ball
to James Lowe.
Porter for the third time.
The hits keep coming.
Gibson Park shifts it to the right as Ireland
trying to make some progress here in the 22.
Sexton just at wall of white jerseys with the toy again.
Behind the back ball trying to unlock
to the left.
Josh Vanderfleer.
Sexton.
Over the top he goes.
Bundy Aki yet again.
Beautiful ball to Lowe on the inside.
Needs help.
There's Mustins all over him.
Banses.
No clear lead.
And a varnish for the Irish side.
Porter.
Nice dummy from the front row forward from Lenster.
A free play here for the Irish side with advantage.
Gibson Park.
Still got the pinnally advantage.
Across they'll go.
The cross kick from Henshaw.
And Ireland will come back.
You're always in contact with the Tekler.
Goes to ground.
No clear release.
So even if he stays on his feet,
as the attacker assists there,
he's throwing the guy to ground.
He has to release before he can get on the ball.
Bundy Aki have that for a carry down the middle.
I thought he was going to go all the way.
Showed a clean set of heels.
This African defence got back in numbers and quickly
so they could get off the line and start putting their
typical shots in.
There were some brilliant tackles in there.
Franz Malhover upending Andrew Porter amongst many others.
But we knew it was going to be a tight effort, Alan.
We've only got three points on the scoreboard so far.
They're really off, celebrate, really off the ball.
You get a look at the penalty there to see
he went all, never released the tackle player
before he then got on the ball.
Four points.
It was a good spot on Ben O'Kee.
Very quick.
There's some good news for Ireland.
Gary Ringrose has passed his HIA
and will return to the field shortly.
That is great news for the Irish side.
Stay on the goal!
The crowd loved that they kicked for the corner
because here comes Callaghan out to the front.
Van der Flier peels around.
It's a bet, hasn't?
Van de Aki.
Their most dangerous runner tonight.
Still the Irish Wave comes at South Africa.
Gibson Park to the right.
forwards quickly regathering themselves for the next wave.
Peter O'Manny.
Gibson Park looks both ways.
Again, it's Van der Flier.
Ireland inching their way closer to the spring box right.
Beautiful play.
Sexton throws a dummy.
He gets so close to Johnny Sexton.
No, there it is!
Head for Hines!
To the right.
No, the numbers there!
Ireland will score and they put it down.
Mack Hansen rips one in for the Irish.
And the crowd are rocked.
Let's start the brass.
Well, that's a beautiful bit of play.
Johnny Sexton gets so close.
The scramble from South Africa.
And it goes wide into the hands of the Moustachio at Mack Hansen
who gets over for Ireland's first score.
Seven points if Sexton can put this one over.
What a moment for Mack Hansen.
Born and bred in Canberra, Australia.
He played super rugby for the Brumbies.
He was actually convinced to come play in or go play in Ireland
by conic coach Andy Friend.
He qualifies for Ireland through his Irish-born mother
and he has another try on the big stage.
He's head of the head of this game.
These type of games, it's probably everything you dream of growing up.
Well, he might have to pitch himself.
Johnny Sexton from the right-hand side.
I think we've got the right pitch as it's come.
Gave it in 2009 in Dublin for his country.
Four, six nations titles.
Too many other titles to list right now as he lines up the extra two.
Does Sexton.
It's straight through the middle.
It's Ireland's seventh, South Africa three.
And the flag's off line at 35 minutes.
It was a fifth pass to James Lowe.
Across the face of the defenders.
It cut out about three defenders that pass.
James Lowe just holding his feet.
Good hands, the catch and pass.
He felt like they earned that score.
Some brilliant attack.
Really nice from the guys in the Emerald Green.
And going for the attacking line-outs as well.
He's paid full value for their seven points.
Khaleesi has it for South Africa.
And Yolendi puts a kick over the top.
A one bounce.
And just like that, the spring box.
Putting on the pressure against Ireland.
We've seen some bullish touches from Yolendi with ball in hand.
That was a delicate one.
Lovely little touch over the top.
I don't mind that, you know.
You've got currently Irons out there.
He'll chase anything and he's quick.
Ronan Kelleher.
To the middle.
And contested.
Gibson Park.
Ireland running upfield now.
Doris.
Penalty Ireland.
This will help them get down the field.
Fabulous carry from Doris.
It was Detoy who was lying on the wrong side.
That's what can happen if you get the dominant carries.
So you get through the contact like that.
You can often leave tacklers stranded on the wrong side
and they were liable to get penalised.
The Irish forwards on a 52% on their game line success.
So far in this tournament coming into this game.
Talk about game line success.
What a joy to have Bundy Aki in the centres.
What a joy to be watching him.
A lovely little change of pace on the width there.
One of the standout performers of this World Cup so far, Bundy Aki.
What a venue for this cliffhanger.
Ireland in the 15th match.
Win streak currently 60.
There's Aki again, flies into the line.
Doris loops around.
Gets a good ball and a good tackle in from Khaleesi.
Gipson Park changes direction.
Bunderflair.
Aki again this time.
Deolendi's there.
Two of the bulkier inside centres in World Cup.
Use it!
OK, no.
Down now.
Javison, Gipson Park.
Now he replaces Connemarie.
It's come off.
The only change.
It's a good find, thank you.
Tonga.
Arden, sir.
Let's it go backwards.
And Damian Vilymser is there.
The fullback to tidy up for South Africa.
First receiver, Yvan Etzebeth.
Takes in a couple Irish players.
Manila Bok on the left boot down the field.
Chance for a counter here.
Keenan does really well.
Does the fullback.
So he's up-ended.
Ring rose again.
Tackle!
Etzebeth has him.
Sacher for Rosers.
The battle at the breakdown.
No lift.
Big ball over the top.
James Low puts a kick through.
And this one will go up the backdoor.
Options.
See her.
You mentioned it during that passage down.
The battle at the breakdown.
Drumroll 22.
Who's this come?
It's been so good already.
So many threats in the jackal.
Which means that everyone, technically,
and in terms of their urgency,
has got to be so good in attack as well.
Such a great contest.
This is what Keenan gives you.
The roaming.
Say, missus, good one last one.
Runner.
Really good, that's what I want.
You're watching the best players in the world here tonight.
Hey, crosses over.
Little pull, then it comes.
Cross New Zealand, Italy, Uruguay, Namibia.
All the finals will take place here.
October 14th and 15th from that pull.
Fine.
Six.
This one goes down the middle side.
Still with South Africa.
Here comes Odinsa behind the back of the box.
Close and wide.
To Chester and Colby.
He spins up.
Good tackle on him.
Score to try in the Rugby World Cup final in Japan last year.
And that breakdown has been run by Ireland.
And the crowd will let you know that.
Well, case in point.
That's Jasper Visa on the carry.
I know exactly what you mean.
I saw a same picture.
He's at six feet, can't believe it.
I'm watching it.
He's not an easy man to take down
by any stretch of the imagination.
And yet, he got shot there.
The vandal player ended up sneaking in on the pill and robbing it.
Guys, is it the final team?
There he is, gets underneath.
But just before that, it was a brilliant display of tackling.
The back row just working together so nicely.
Steven, Steven.
It's pretty similar to Johnny Sexton's reaction in back play.
You can just see exactly what it means to Ireland's leaders.
Peter Omani gave them a stirring pump-up before the game.
They are here to play today.
They really are.
And so far, the scoreboard chose that as well.
Bundyaki again goes in that middle channel.
Behind the backpaw, to Vona Flau.
Ireland, back to the right-hand side.
They go.
Porter is there.
Just a skip, Ireland.
Tackle!
Just with this up.
Gibson Park.
Sexton, quick hands.
Ty Thurlong, the Oxford Bull is there.
James Ryan, claps us forward.
For Ireland, but Peter Stepp, the tour has it.
Oh, difficult pass for Khaleesi to take.
Almost.
Oh, my barnage, it's halftime.
Ireland coming through here.
And that is the first 40 minutes gone.
They're insane.
Denny North of Paris.
It's the full B-battle at the 2023 rugby World Cup.
When you would be close and it is, the halftime score
sees Ireland lead South Africa 7-3 from a packed start to France.
Last time Ireland played South Africa,
both countries scored two tries each in the second half.
The difference being a single penalty by Johnny Sexton.
But tonight at start to France, it's 7-3.
Ireland leads South Africa.
Mack Hansen on the board for this Irish side.
A big second 40 awaits us, Metri.
Well, we knew it was going to be close.
Previous meetings, limited to Gaffer.
Six at Max and the crowd here stand to their feet.
The balance in the crowd, slight tip towards the Irish, perhaps.
There's the South African legend.
Familiar face.
We see him around the world, the seventh circuit.
Brian Havana.
One of the best to have done it out there on the dingaling.
Record try, score a full South Africa.
He watches on.
Bungie, Ember Numbie.
Gears up for our second half.
Ring Rose is good.
He's back on his feet.
Mustard.
One of the big imposing South African forwards.
And the Irish side stacked with talented players.
Sexton, their leader.
Andy Farrell looks on from Ireland.
You're watching the second half between Ireland and South Africa.
From starting start to France at the 2023 Rugby World Cup.
Ireland on the left, lead 73 against South Africa.
Fendi Aki with a take.
The world welcome to you for the thrilling Poulbi match-up.
I'm down the staffer.
Pitch side net.
You need to use the right side.
Great Britain Olympic time.
Mitch on here.
Comes Vissa for South Africa.
Straight away.
Sorry, what?
Pinnolly?
A quick pinch.
Mustard.
Pinnolly.
To the line for the spring box.
And hold on.
Fours on the wrong side.
Fix the ball coming out.
It's a bet.
Again in trouble.
Four whites.
Yeah, I saw that in the rut.
He was lying on the wrong side.
The ball coming out.
Comes out on your side.
We saw that penalising the first half.
The tackle lying on the wrong side.
I think he probably is a good call from the referee
or from his assistant.
They did disrupt that rut, ball for Ireland.
Even Estabeth came from a hell of a long way
to make that first tackle.
He started on their own 10 meet lines
so that he could hit the half way.
Just watching him two running.
He's got a different ball.
Just have to take it quick.
So he's running at full tilt
and he was the first to arrive
to make the hit on Bendi Aki,
but then slightly earlier than that.
Okay, let's start with good space this half.
There he is lying on the wrong side.
See, disrupting the Ireland rut.
No, it's a bet.
His ideal holiday isn't to the beaches of Greece,
but to the gym.
He's coached by a knee number, looks on.
Gallagher to the back.
That's a great line-up from Ireland.
Aki throws a short ball to...
He's standing apart in a ring, Rose.
And then Gibson Park puts one over the top.
It's a very good kick from the Irish number nine.
And it's on Africa that a captain there, 22.
Let's go, please.
No changes to either side at half time,
so the South African Bumpscourt,
they're lying in white.
Confirmed it, it doesn't, already out.
The suggestion was Peter Marni saying that hit back
on his nose before it went out.
I think it might have done, you know.
It looked like it did catch him.
Maybe it was just a lock of hair.
And that's bound to get in the way with Fuff the Clack.
Mosta takes as the captain, Sir Khaleesi,
goes upfield.
South Africa player here, 20-21.
Captain South Africa to a series one of the British Irish line.
Some of these players were playing against South Africa.
Hansen throws it to his full back.
Keenan cuts back in nicely.
They link well, and then he runs into his own player
who was pulled up.
That won't count as a tackle.
But Ireland still with possession.
Playing on, Peter Marni.
Sexton.
Oh, that is a nice kick yet again.
Two in a row from the Irish, halfbacks.
And he's saying it's touched,
so he wants a piece of this line out.
Whether they get it or not,
that's threaded that like a noodle down the touch line.
There's not really much on there.
Look at the space he's aimed for there.
He's putting on absolute sixpence so that it bounces out.
Okay, you've got to stay out as we're seeing this.
They're clearly out.
They don't have one.
65 caps for South Africa.
Interference close by in the line-up.
Ireland getting involved now against South Africa's attack.
We've got it off South Africa through.
Five for Kool.
It's never a five.
Marni getting up in front of Ezebeth
on that occasion.
No easy task.
A five-in-five with five line-out time.
A massive opportunity for the Irish here.
Most of the returns are favour.
Peter stepped into a hazard for South Africa.
Never on the ball, just the body, no.
For the contest we've seen from the big men.
Okay, use it!
Hold here.
Fuff the clack.
Plays alongside Jesse Creel in Japan.
Inside, guys.
Downtown is the kick to the halfway line.
Pin point from South Africa.
The side of the half to me.
It's an absolute masterclass in line-out jump here at the moment.
The way the lifters are getting...
The speed with which those jumps are getting the eggs.
The lifters are trying them, getting right close together
so they're getting the jumper to the maximum height.
Get that, though.
Six line-outs lost for Ireland.
Kellehert improves his stats.
He's through the middle!
On the fly up.
Aki comes in down to the halfway line for the Irish side.
Kellehert again.
Takes some kicks off.
Kellehert comes in, wants the pill, stays with...
The men in green.
Use it!
Six and two.
They're right inside.
He lets his forwards attack a bit more.
Penalty, South Africa.
He's not out of the way.
Holding on.
Five.
We've got some changes coming for South Africa.
RG Snimon's coming on, so too is Quagga Smith.
And so is Jean Klein,
who has previously played at international level for Ireland.
So this is going to be a very interesting experience for him
coming up against his old nation.
Three members of the bomb squad about to take the field here.
And there's Kellehert getting over it.
Well, he just hesitated a little bit on that one
because he wasn't sure if he was legal.
But there was nothing illegal about this.
Visa, getting his legs nice and wide
to allow himself to get low over that rock.
Here's the light you mentioned.
Fuff the clock will line up this penalty attempt.
Third most kept.
So happens to come off of all time behind the late U.S. for the best as it.
And for Rhee Dupree, the rugby World Cup winner.
From inside, here's half.
Fuff the clock.
As if the uplock has come bouncing back.
And flying up there was Cheslin Colby for South Africa.
Somehow the springbox have it.
Kellehert goes to the right.
Umba Nabi's there.
This may work out better for the springbox
if they do score a try.
Jasper Visser crunches forward.
The clock finds.
It's a bit.
Who's picked up?
That is a highlight reel for social media.
Yeah, but it's a bit.
It's been thrown out of the party.
Damien.
Time is a month to boot.
Four, five and eight.
Subs, four, five and eight.
Bounce back, absolute chaos.
But how about this?
The big tree uprooted.
And it's going to be his last play of the match
because he's coming off.
He's going to be angry.
He'll be very angry about that.
William, it's a bit.
But the replacements are on.
You mentioned that earlier.
Oxen chair is also coming on as well.
So that's four replacements on the bench.
John Clayne, Erichia Snemann.
He's got the Smith as well.
There he goes.
It's a bit.
The Viking they call him.
Erichia Snemann plays his rugby in Munster.
He's been left off.
A defence ball.
It's an attack.
He's offloading.
Tight hit, feet underneath.
He had the injury.
RJ Snemann since 2019.
But made an impressive impact on this workup already.
And that's Crocker Smith.
I love watching him play the game.
An all-rounder.
You might see him slotting a few different positions today.
We have the Olympian Crocker Smith.
There's even kits of goes off the field.
Six.
So now seven-months to go over again.
Five for Ireland.
Big shot from the spring box.
Ireland pick it up the back.
They hit the deck.
And South Africa rewarded with a penalty five out.
There it is.
Number 12, ceiling, hands on the ground.
Kandiyaki puts his hands up, the ceiling off.
We're going to go again at scrumtime.
The South African engine room.
Fight up.
Timing.
Full force.
Oh, they put the item back.
A roller skates there.
What a hit.
What a shove.
There's substitutes with South Africa doing the business.
Cross.
Fine.
It's a sport that means so much for these two countries.
Reset down far side.
Reset with down the far side.
We're going to move it over here.
Very good.
Okay, keep that up.
Same message.
We've got to keep the height to the side.
The both of you.
155 is watching the scrums and being in them.
Chesham Colby right here in front of us on the far touch line,
but I think the action initially at least is going to be up front
for the spring box.
Cross.
Fine.
Nice.
Six.
Elbow up.
Vantage.
Lucy collapsing.
Elbow.
The Varnish for South Africa with four of the Bonsquat members
on the field.
The Elendi beautiful ball on the outside.
South Africa will power over.
Cheslam Colby with the drive.
Forget low-chilling.
He's electric 24-7.
Well, we saw.
We hoped it would come to him eventually.
And it was Marnie LaBeouf that delivered the goods.
Cheslam Colby the Olympian.
He's magic in open space.
And there was plenty of it down on this touch line.
The only easier running to have.
He dots down and it's a statement score for the spring box
after those two scrums where they absolutely pushed Ireland
back towards their own tri-line.
And you called it.
The wood from Colby just lurking on this left-hand touch line
so that Africa have the lead now, 8-7.
Referee Beno Keefe.
Sorry, I've just lost you.
Just checking something.
Yep.
Thank you.
All good.
Shot clock back on, please.
All good is the call from Beno Keefe.
Marnie LaBeouf lands this one up.
URC.
Record point scorer and tri-assist in recent times
for the Stormers from Cape Town.
Thank you.
Baby, just Tess your confidence to me after this kick.
LaBeouf, taking his time.
The clock ticks.
Five seconds to take the kick.
Just pulls it to the left-hand side.
But so now we go on front, 8-7.
Thanks to this try from Chesham Colby.
2-5, 2-5.
We can restart.
Well, we just saw a picture there.
It was Mack Hansen.
Probably thought he was taking out of the ball a little bit
with the running lines.
But South Africa won't mind.
Some really big changes for both sides.
Marco van Stavens come on for the skipper,
Sia Khaleesi, while Ian Mindersen and Dan Sheehan
have both come on for Ireland.
Thanks, Nan.
That's a lot of changes indeed.
As Ireland looked to run it back with their number, 8.
Kailen Doris studying psychology at university.
College doublet.
Sextor pulls it up.
Well-fielded in the end.
Killing space, 10 metres.
They're going to pull back Devin Bulamsa.
Hold.
Now Sia Khaleesi will look from the sideline now,
after being replaced.
Inside.
Feels kind of early to make that change.
Sextor.
Again, to the heavens of that kick.
His fullback chases.
Hugo Keenan is there against Bulamsa.
And he stays with the South African side.
But the clock tries to dig in.
Finds his fly-off under pressure.
Krill has it.
Jesse Krill cuts in.
Does the outside centre.
The clock to Oxencheck.
Behind the back he goes.
Le Boc finds Bulamsa with a beautiful step.
Take in Bulamsa.
With some fancy footwork for South Africa.
Great presence of mind to let that one go.
Krill on the charge.
And there's Bulamsa.
Fancy footwork indeed.
Steps out of it.
That is beautiful.
Such poise for a big man, Devin Bulamsa.
Good take.
Ian Henderson, the replacement.
And it turns it in beautifully.
Dan Sheenan.
He's rugby World Cup debut.
Hasn't played for Ireland since he's put in the warm-up game against England.
But he's on the park.
On this mammoth stage.
In this mammoth game.
Charge down is there from Anfield-Snowman.
Advantage.
Low with a kick.
Offside play.
The spike ping is towards the upper tower.
Sorry, I didn't see that.
Offside, guys.
Perhaps Ireland will make a couple of those changes down here.
Ian Henderson.
Jamison.
Devs have been without a doubt that time.
Don't dummy.
Get that line out.
Okay, he might go the other way.
Yeah, I haven't worked on that occasion.
They came away with it.
Someone stood in someone's hand.
But I haven't seen that, sorry.
We've got the pin already here.
Stents now.
Sexton might just want to steer this control.
There's a little bit in Ireland's favour.
Feels like, as so often the case with the spring box.
When they make those changes,
it always dives the momentum in their favour.
Never onside on that.
Charge down round by the rock.
Did that guy make the catch?
Hats off to him.
I think he did.
Brilliant bit of skill.
Got this wonderful crowd to the front.
You know, Manny.
Here come Ireland now.
Aki releases.
Sexton.
An intricate move.
Brings in low there.
Leeds one in short space.
Form a basketball player.
Now rugby star.
Here comes Doris again.
The 25-year-old carries well for Ireland.
Yeah, good counter.
And then a counter there.
Pocha Smith getting heavily involved.
Very good counter.
South Africa.
He's so boosted up.
He's a MacGyver of rugby.
He can solve any issue.
Ken Cocher.
Could have been accuracy from Ireland.
Get the break down.
This was the set piece.
Play with the wrap around a little inside ball,
but Sefka pretty wise to it.
James Lowe making a few metres.
It was a carry for the back of this.
Doris, where the post-contact meters.
Then they were inaccurate.
There's still a break down.
Big counter up coming in for Sefka.
You really feel now they've got the fire underneath them.
One point the difference on the scoreboard.
Plenty of time to go.
And thank goodness, because I'm enjoying this, Alan.
And the first off, shot by.
And the same's continuing here.
This is Cool Beat.
Number one and two side in the world.
Happen to collide here.
It's Penalty to Ireland.
That's the back of the scrum.
What a scrum.
Careful, guys, careful, careful, careful, careful.
Guys, tight hit, fully overextended.
Tight hit, fully overextended, collapsing.
You heard from referee.
And they keep saying the tight head.
Over-extending.
Now Herbert.
Looks like he did go down there.
Too long with his body shape.
Just got under the pressure there from Andrew Porter.
The crowd hashes.
As Johnny Sexton, the world rugby player of the year,
a few years ago, lines up.
A potential lead for his country.
Sexton is a smooth operator.
And Alan, go back in the lead.
10-8, as we approach the hour mark.
As we approach the hour mark.
Where it's Alan Johnny Sexton indeed.
No lights needed from the Ireland coaching box.
You might as well have a coach out there
run around the 10-shirt.
The 38-year-old, so consistent, so sharp.
He's used to winning six nations championships with Ireland,
but boy, he'd love a World Cup.
You wonder, is this a precursor for what's to come for Ireland?
Yeah, unbelievable stat.
They have never got out of the quarterfinals
at a rugby World Cup.
Nice take from the Irish side.
Can this be their year?
2019 Japan, they lost.
2-0, 48 points to 14.
Gibson Park has to pick quickly and scoop.
There's the scum off.
Okay, that battle continues.
You're fine.
In close quarters.
Use it!
Mundiaki.
No, no.
He relieves it as Ian Henderson has a go.
He's third, rugby World Cup, what experience he brings.
Captain number 78.
Use it!
Nine!
Timing!
Gibson Park.
What he was putting right on?
So, Villamsa.
Damian Villamsa takes well, then drives up field
for the spring box.
But the clock throws a dummy.
They've got numbers wide.
No, hand off!
Peter Steftertweet.
Turning around the back was John Clay.
Going against his...
...team-mates, currently.
Again, he carries hard.
What a story, flying both for Ireland and Sudabhraga
in his career.
Kurt Learonsa, with a lot of traffic in front of him.
Marnie LeBocke finds Villamsa to be left behind by the Olendi
and that's frustration for South Africa.
Well, there's his aerial skill.
And he's so good, you don't expect.
Air isn't...
A little dummy, a little pump.
The Olendi was about to come underneath, I think, on the cut line.
I think Villamsa's frustrated with himself, the hesitation.
That's got the Irish crowd on their feet here.
There's that difference.
Another change for South Africa.
Trevor Inyakar, he has come onto the field for Franz Malmöver.
Another forward.
Techie Pot.
Third Rugby World Cup, with Russell, 92, his traffic.
Inyakar, he...
Oh, ask me, Olino.
Coach!
Bind!
Sixth!
Valens' possession is their crowd.
Resets.
Kerry Zonders, Perrin, Atmosphere, we've seen.
The didn't dummy, guys, hold the weight.
There's sense for everyone, lads.
Time's off for the shoot.
Okay, guys.
Yeah, hold it, hold it.
The end of the piece.
No, it was like going down the top.
Both of them came through.
Okay, Olen.
You're going to restart.
FAN R embaixo
Okay, time's on...
Reset.
What an interlude, missing the fields of Athenrye.
Ring out in this stadium.
Crouch!
Bind!
Sit!
Ten-half of the hard-minute rugby.
Look forwards.
And the spring blocks, Cole went back.
Straight, pushing straight.
Oh, they're not saying straight.
Wow, with a combo of Porter and Furlong.
Fongi, shot.
The props of the Island Scrum.
So, water just for the kick in, Arnau.
Being demolished on this occasion.
You can see its power gets underneath.
Jimmy, how are we looking at it?
Sit up now.
Under the chest there, Furlong.
Driving him up and in.
Text post, good.
Rani LeBotte.
South Africa, with his country watching.
Dressed in such brilliant colour.
The rainbow nation.
Thus, to take back the lead.
Stand still.
The red numbers getting very low.
As Rani LeBotte looks on.
Unsuccessful.
Subs.
Well, the question mark remains.
We're on the goal-kicking snap.
The worst goal-kicking record at this World Cup of any team.
Coming into this, just 10 out of 18 attempts.
And, unfortunately, Rani LeBotte,
only 40% kicking, coming into this.
The question mark remains.
The big changes coming through both sides.
Finlay, Bilham, Ryan Baird and Robbie Henshaw
have all come onto the field.
Omani and Rikrose both coming off for Ireland.
Dua for South Africa.
Dionne Furi has come onto the field.
Mahbongi, Mahbongi Nabi.
The big changes of both sides.
Who can finish off strongly?
Here comes Kwakus Smith.
Loves eating green millies.
Not scared, is Smith?
No, wait, wait, yep.
First touch for Dionne Furi.
He can be the oldest test.
Debbie Tuntin, South Africa history.
Rani's first cap is nearly 36 years of age.
And, now, we have a penalty.
The halfway line.
OK, guys, 16.
Green was offside, 16.
Nazir Azen's barking orders.
And, now, we've got a right-for-phone
down the walkie-talkie,
should say to the touchline.
We saw the traffic light again.
You've got a wonder.
A look
on Andrew Porter's face.
Going into that collision
with Faka Smith.
Grimace, the determination.
Perfect.
After Klerch can be more in determination
between the uprights.
And, boy, this team could do with it now.
The 31-year-old.
Bangs it downfield.
And misses.
That's two different attacks from
South Africa.
Keeps Ireland in the lead.
10-8.
And that's a change of
Spramharves for Ireland.
Jamison Park, Gibson Park,
coming off the field.
Or Connemarie, the very experienced
Connemarie is coming off.
119 total caps for
Murray. He's on the field.
Now, here comes Cuocas-Muthier again.
Into the freight.
Nick Nainby's brother.
The extinct subspecies of Zebra
known as the Cuocas.
To the right comes Willemser,
out there.
He's in the lead.
It's a straight on attack.
Jhon Klain carries now.
Born in Krugerstorp,
near Johannesburg.
Deolendi cut down at the halfway line.
Pickup before
Fuffer-Klagdau.
Willemser to the sky.
Lowes there for Ireland.
Misses it.
It's a lower pickup.
We'll pick up a bit of territory.
They're in their way. They're in their way.
Knock on.
Massively in the balance, this game, isn't it?
I'll watch it.
Willem says he had a pretty all-court game today.
I've seen him running into contact.
We've seen him stepping around it.
In that case, you've got boots of wool.
What are you doing?
referee going to keep nearly taking out Parker Smith,
or they'd probably take more than a swinging arm
to put Smith down.
Moving forward.
Players like Smith allow him to do the 7-1 split on the bench.
He's got an outstanding skill set at home in the game of 7s.
He can carry, he can pass, and do high balls.
Coach!
He's got the Smith future in the Olympic Games.
Seth!
The ankle plays across from 7s to 15s.
OK!
So over again.
Two-time rugby world cup champions.
We've trailed now.
Yeah, great work, great work.
The only champion to lose a cool game.
It happened in 2019 against New Zealand.
They lost, we're only in the stages.
Carry there from Oxford, check.
And the plays are dropping for the Sharks Island.
You turn over. Pinched a swipe.
That's why they're the topside in the world.
They're up to do things like that.
That's a good carry.
Moxham, check.
Backed up by Trevor.
Neocardic.
We're good. OK, we're good.
Time bit gone.
Fath lively, as ever is made.
Trying to make the difference for his team.
They're charging that one down
and deflecting it out for this line-up.
Ireland will throw in just outside their 22.
In error, it's been problematic in this game.
And these are important moments now.
Dan Sheehan.
He was well-nominated for World Rugby Breakthrough Play
of the Year in 2022.
Aki is there.
OK, that's good now.
Inside their half.
Taking back.
Hold in front!
Down the throat of Damian Valensa.
Will he kick or will he run?
Throw is the big left-footed step.
Fast there for a mock-up and started.
So, there we go. Working the way upfield.
Playing.
Looked as well. And here comes Ergius.
Stay there on the burst! The Viking!
Sailing towards the 22.
So, there we go. Numbers on the run inside.
LeBotte.
Creole.
Peter Steff to Toy.
Loser's possession.
And it's a good tackle as well.
In from Connemarie.
Do we not have a knock-on at the touch-by?
So, there we go.
Well, it looked like he knocked that on in the tackle.
Time off.
Guys, South Africa Ball.
26, then.
South Africa Ball was touched by Greenfield.
There's a lot of folks and things.
Been late.
BOM also getting a look over.
Touched by Greenhand in the tackle.
Timo confirmed it.
Great hands from LeBotte.
And a great line from Steinman.
The big, striding second row.
And I think that Toy was just trying to lift it.
It's always winger outside him as Aronson.
It's party time at the Rugby World Cup.
OK, we're going to restart.
It's party time in the stands.
It's a little bit more tense on the pitch.
Going into the 10 minutes to go, Mark.
It's so important now, these players.
Coming into it was a lot made of this game.
I think it's the Irish management beforehand.
And they were saying, yes, there is.
But the consequences are less than they will be
in the future in this competition.
So, hopefully the players are allowed to feel the freedom of play.
With two points difference on the scoreboard.
One versus two.
This is going to be tense.
And it's about their ability to stay in the moment,
stay processed, stay composed.
I don't need the pool currently.
10 points to nine over Sarabaga as well.
A take for the Springboks.
Sean Kline, the only 140 matches for Munster.
Going against
Friends
in this Rugby World Cup pool game.
Advantage for the Springboks.
They're inside the 22.
But the clock pushing a few bodies away.
Little advantage.
Here comes Kochesma.
He's hit hard.
No, no, over here.
Ireland player.
Ireland comes around the side.
Changes bind.
Side injury.
No, it was the same all the whole time.
I don't know if it was
a tight burn, a little bit.
I don't know if it was a tight burn initially
with the infringement
around the side in the mall.
It's one mall.
We might see another one rolling.
There he is.
Initially it looked like he came through the middle,
which would have been fine.
I thought he pulled out perhaps under the referee's instruction,
but penalised.
No.
South Africa's chance
would tend to go.
They're 5 metres up.
Deion Faruik.
Not accurate.
Well, Ireland line-up coach Paul O'Connor
was asked before this whether they thought
introduction of Deion Faruik would be
a weakness.
And he kind of played it down, but...
3-1.
It was a back row play.
He also played soccer, transferred
and gives them that
variety.
He's got plenty of life experience coming in
at 36, but not a huge
amount of game experience at this level.
That's our mark. Keep the watch.
Come on for his ninth today.
Fresh up in these moments,
starting to boil.
He knew it would be an issue when Malcolm
Marks was injured
and no longer take part
with the South African side of this
World Cup.
Ireland coach!
The chance for them to clear their lines.
5-1.
6-1.
BEEP.
Finally, perhaps.
Big forward pack, Carling in Ireland.
They're able to kick towards
the touch line using James Low.
BEEP.
That is a stunning kick
from the Irish winger.
BEEP.
That is huge.
That was
absolute giant nudge.
Huge change coming for Ireland
here. Johnny Sexton
is coming off the field.
Of course, he is a fan favourite.
He is a legend of Irish rugby.
He's been the heart and soul of this team
all night. He's going to come off
for the last eight minutes of this absolute
nail biter, Jack Crowley.
He's going his replacement.
Sexton leaves his country with a lead.
Can they hold on to that?
Can they hold it on by Sarah
Redire here?
After taking it in,
owego South Africa
here, off the middle when
taking it in, off the middle when
started, gets a beautiful ball
fromMadhall.
Corporation
second catcher,
With possession, but the clock, can't get it, Arlen, Pylen.
Who's there? Pylen.
And then it's been left behind, Hoofdownfield from Arlen.
A stunning steal, and they drive back to Springbox.
Jesse Krill.
Feats one.
South Africa.
They've got turnover at the last breaktime.
May have lost it again. Arlen, an attack. Here they come.
Ball splits free to the left-hand side.
Another look for some magic.
Keenan, the fullback.
Brought down inside the 22.
Here we go, release.
Connemarie.
With this crowd urging them on, good ball again. Jack Crowley on the field.
The cheers continue. Ian Henderson, the Ulsterman.
Behind the back ball.
Just held on there from Hugo Keenan.
The Fox doing well.
Porter.
Tanks a strong hit.
There's Robbie Henshaw, looks to attack.
Arlen, looking at the options here.
Tyburn carries well again in the URC with Munster.
They go to the pocket.
Nice successful attempt, but they need to have a go.
Got a scum.
Taking back.
It's going to be a five-year scum, because it's charged down.
Been touched in the air.
Scum did.
Yeah, there it is. Touched it, Lende.
Doing a good work to charge it down, but it's actually...
They really broke up.
Crill.
Scragged in court.
And invited Arlen to counter up.
Another change for Arlen.
Andrew Porter coming off the field.
He's been instrumental today in that set-piece.
Such has been the physicality of this game.
I think it's a well-deserved break for him.
Yeah, it really is. Been a thick of it.
He's on the park.
Steadkill coming in.
Great shot there in the RSI.
We're talking about corners.
Compose yourselves in these moments.
Just over five to play.
They're there in a huddle.
And South Africa have made the final change of their bench.
They're low in back.
Covers Reiner. He's onto the field.
Back to clerk coming off.
A new Reiner who's got on the field.
And sometimes you set the only back.
Fan favourite.
Three years at Northampton Saints before he moved to France.
The second quickest in Rugby World Cup mystery
behind the one he set in 2019 against Canada.
Come on.
Goal.
APPLAUSE
Down the alley.
Put this game away.
Five minutes to play.
Their lead South Africa ten-eight.
Time's off.
Straight down.
Don't use your head on the shoulder.
It's your ball.
Re-set please.
It's heading hands-time.
You can barely watch.
Two points on the scoreboard.
Five minutes to play.
Ireland's setting up camp at the scrum.
Five metres off.
It's an African line.
The experience of Connemore to put into this scrum.
Coach!
Fine!
Here we go.
As the world watches.
What's up?
Pedal the island.
Unshable second time.
You can hear the roar.
Shot called on the line, please.
Instability.
Mack Hansen just came up to this near side
to fire the crowd up.
I don't think they need it, Mack.
They're all on their feet.
They're loving line.
Substitute front row for Ireland.
We'll be very, very pleased to get one over
on the box pack.
A massive moment in the game for Ireland.
Jack Crowley.
Pivotal roll for the Munster side,
winning the URC this year.
From close range.
To make it a five-point lead.
Crowley has his name in the box.
It's 13 points to rate.
Ireland leads South Africa.
With three minutes to play.
Colby looks to the skies.
A hint of despair in the South African eyes now.
Down the middle goes South Africa.
Nice lift from Ireland.
Can they close out this game?
They carry green.
It's a big kick yet again.
Two in a row.
Manila Bok launches the counter.
The flowers being held,
and there's a bunch of green jerseys around there.
No.
Rahnach retains possession for South Africa.
Villams up.
Magic needed from some of the playmakers.
Justin Colby.
Can't get free on this occasion to the half-way line.
10 overs, good.
A pinch and another steal from Ireland.
Unbelievable from Bandiaki.
10 overs, good.
And on the other side of the ball, low again.
Chips this way.
Colby, his opposite number.
90 seconds left.
South Africa's...
chance with ball in hand.
Big hit as well, Rahnach wants possession.
Then she waits.
Turns it behind the back.
The Bok fires Jesse Krill
to the half-way line.
The tackles keep coming from Ireland.
Fountains, second man.
Hands on.
In the advantage for South Africa.
Villams up.
They pass away in the tackle, and then eventually...
BEEP
OK, you've got two penalties.
One penalty here for Offi.
Up again.
Chairs, one here.
From the South African side.
Offi, they're not a group short of belief.
They said coming in for this, they love the pressure cooker.
Wow, it's dialed right up now.
Marnie Le Bois.
So much said about his kicking in this game.
In his shots at goal, he's been questionable.
He's missed a few.
Well, that's a nice nudge.
He's given his back.
An inviting platform to play here.
The drama...
unfolding in front of us.
That's Dr. Fritz.
Final play.
Ireland lead, 13-8.
Therese.
Goes to Peter Stefter Tweet.
South Africa.
Mourning towards the Thailand.
Yeah, Lendi's in there as well.
Tideburn.
The Irish defender on the side.
They've defended supposedly.
Where is it?
They're trying to dig us out.
It's there.
Has it come out?
Ireland.
Have done it.
The number one team in the world.
Irishers are smiling tonight.
They've taken one step closer
to their rugby World Cup dream.
They're beating the spring box.
It's been an extraordinary evening in Paris.
There'll be tears.
There'll be celebrations.
80,000 fans here and millions around the world.
Have witnessed one of the great battles
in rugby World Cup history.